Guide to the South Africa Now Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Documentaries, 1980-1991, undated; Series III
  - Tape D88: ABC -- Three documentaries on Africa -- South Africa and Zimbabwe, Undated; 1 (Box 375)
  - Tape D90: Mozambique: Riding Out the Storm (Alter-Ciné), 1989; 1 (Box 376)
  - Tape D92: Chain of Tears (original), 1989 May 26; 1 (Box 377)
  - Tape D93: South Carolina Educational Television (S.C. ETV) - New Liberation Wars: Angola, 1987 September 27; 1 (Box 378)
  - Tape D94: Center for Defense Information (CDI) -- America's Defense Monitor: Covert Action, 1987 October 22; 1 (Box 379)
  - Tapes D95-D96: Scenes from the Class Struggle in Portugal, Parts 1 and 2, Undated; 2 (Box 380–381)
  - Tape D97: Out of Sight -- Out of Mind, 1989 July 18; 1 (Box 382)
  - Tape D98: You Have Struck a Rock, Undated; 1 (Box 383)
  - Tapes D99-D100: Peter Davis -- South Africa: The Nuclear File, Parts 1 and 2, 1989 July 16; 2 (Box 384–385)
  - Tape D101: Namibia: Nuclear Reactions, 1989; 1 (Box 386)
  - Tape D103: PAC -- My Land/Minha Terra (Portuguese), Early 1989; 1 (Box 387)
  - Tape D106: Namibian documentary (Nuclear Reactions), Undated; 1 (Box 388)
  - Tape D107: Hidden Farms, Undated; 1 (Box 389)
  - Tape D108: National Film School "Re tua Bona", 1989 December 29; 1 (Box 390)
  - Tape D109: International Defense and Aid Fund (IDAF) -- Any Child Is My Child, 1990 February 1; 1 (Box 391)
  - Tape D110: Isitwalandwe transferred B-roll/stills, Undated; 1 (Box 392)
  - Tape D112: Isitwalandwe: The Story of South African Freedom Charter, 1980; 1 (Box 393)
    See also: Tape D146b and Tape D147.
  - Tape D114: Winnie and Nelson Mandela, Undated; 1 (Box 394)
  - Tape D115: Globalvision/ South Africa Now -- "Mandela: Free at Last" -- PBS Special, 1990 February 12; 1 (Box 395)
    See also: Tape D123a-D123b and Tape D154.
  - Tape D116: "Songs of the Adventurers" (Lesotho mining songs), 1990 February 21; 1 (Box 396)
  - Tapes D117-D118: Kevin Harris -- No Easy Road to Freedom (Tapes 1 and 2), Undated; 2 (Box 397–398)
  - Tape D119: From Street to Struggle: Black Kids in South Africa, 1990 April 25; 1 (Box 399)
  - Tape D120: Killing a Dream, Undated; 1 (Box 400)
  - Tape D121: Center for Defense Information: Poison Winds -- Biological Warfare, 1990 May 30; 1 (Box 401)
  - Tape D122: Center for Defense Information: The Military and the Environment, 1990 February 4; 1 (Box 402)
  - Tapes D123a-D123b: Mandela Free at Last (dub) part 1 and 2, Undated; 2 (Box 403–404)
    See also: Tape D115 and Tape D154.
  - Tape D124: Back to the Motherland, 1990 June 29; 1 (Box 405)
  - Tape D125: Wind of Hope, 1990 June 29; 1 (Box 406)
  - Tape D126: CARE -- Lesotho documentary, 1990 August 28; 1 (Box 407)
  - Tape D127: Fruits of Defiance -- Namibian documentary, Undated; 1 (Box 408)
  - Tape D128: Mozambique: Struggle for Survival, Undated; 1 (Box 409)
  - Tape D129: The World Against Apartheid, 1990 October 13; 1 (Box 410)
  - Tape D130: Kevin Harris -- Rebirth of Namibia, tapes 1 and 2, Undated; 2 (Box 411–412)
    Both tapes have the same tape number (D130).
  - Tape D131: South Africa -- The Wasted Land, 1990 October 30; 1 (Box 413)
  - Tape D131: Garry Brewer: Lady Smith Black Mombozza, 1990 May 15; 1 (Box 414)
  - Tape D132: Tarkari and Coke, 1990 October 31; 1 (Box 415)
  - Tape D133: South Africa Now: "The Breadwinner", 1990 October 18; 1 (Box 416)
  - Tape D134: AIDS -- As Surely as an A.K..., 1990 October 18; 1 (Box 417)
  - Tape D135: A Will to Survive: Black Businessmen in South Africa, Undated; 1 (Box 418)
  - Tape D140: Solomon Mahlango Freedom College (SOMAFCO) -- We've Come a Long Way, 1990 December; 1 (Box 419)
  - Tape D141: Faithful Defiance: A Portrait of Desmond Tutu, Undated; 1 (Box 420)
  - Tapes D142-D143: Mandela in America, Parts 1and 2 (Globalvision), 1990 August; 2 (Box 421–422)
  - Tape D145: World Summit for Children, United Nations (UN): One Day in September, 1991 April; 1 (Box 423)
  - Tape D146b: Isitwalandwe: The Story of the South African Freedom Charter (Part 2 of 2), Undated; 1 (Box 424)
    See also: Tape D112.
  - Tape D147: Isitwalandwe, 1990 May 1; 1 (Box 425)
  - Tape D148: The Anvil and the Hammer, 1990 May 1; 1 (Box 426)
  - Tape D149: Copies of The Anvil and the Hammer; Spear of the Nation; South African Freedom, Undated; 1 (Box 427)
  - Tape D150: Freedom Charter (long version), Undated; 1 (Box 428)
  - Tapes D151-D152: Saamstaan Houses (1 and 2), 1991 April 29; 2 (Box 429–430)
  - Tape D153: Cutdown: Rebirth of a Nation, Undated; 1 (Box 431)
  - Tape D154: Free at Last: Mandela Special, 1990 February 11; 1 (Box 432)
    See also: Tape D115 and Tapes D123a-D123b.
  - Tape D154: Moving On: The Hunger for Land in Zimbabwe, Undated; 1 (Box 433)
- Stock Footage, Circa 1987-1990, undated; Series IV
  The series consists of tapes of stock footage used in the production of South Africa Now. It is arranged sequentially by a tape numbering system used by Globalvision and tape titles used by Globalvision have been preserved.
  - Tape E1: Angola soldiers fighting, 1987 November 4; 1 (Box 434)
  - Tape E3: Dulcie September (funeral footage) -- Paris, Undated; 1 (Box 435)
  - Tape E4: Viz News South Africa "Squatters", Undated; 1 (Box 436)
  - Tape E5: Township Freedom Park/Army Patrol in Township, Undated; 1 (Box 437)
  - Tape E6: South African footage, 1983 December; 1 (Box 438)
  - Tape E7: Cabinda (Angola) oil field, Undated; 1 (Box 439)
  - Tape E8: African scenes from "Lifestyles of the Rich and Famous", Undated; 1 (Box 440)
  - Tape E9: Stephen Reed -- South African footage, Udated; 1 (Box 441)
  - Tape E10: Angola Massacre -- poverty, 1987 November; 1 (Box 442)
  - Tape E15: Army in Alexandra, Undated; 1 (Box 443)
  - Tape E16: Angola -- captured South African Defence Force (SADF) member questioned by Jesse Jackson, Undate; 1 (Box 444)
  - Tape E18: Children on Frontline, Undated; 1 (Box 445)
  - Tape E19: Centre Against Apartheid -- World Conference Against South Africa, United Nations (UN), 1987 May 22; 1 (Box 446)
  - Tape E24: Tutu, from Ron Britt, 1988 May; 1 (Box 447)
  - Tape E31: South African albums, stills, Undated; 1 (Box 448)
  - Tape E32: Clip reel -- Zambia -- Tanzania, Undated; 1 (Box 449)
  - Tape E35: Democratic Convention/Jesse Jackson, 1988; 1 (Box 450–451)
  - Tape E36: Ch. 13 Central Park / Mandela's birthday, 1988 July 18; 1 (Box 452)
  - Tape E37: Fugi TV Central Park / Mandela's birthday, Undated; 1 (Box 453)
  - Tape E40: Stock shots and stills of Sarafina billboard -- "Down 2nd Ave", Undated; 1 (Box 454)
  - Tape E41: Dukakis at Democratic Convention; Dukakis with Tutu, Undated; 1 (Box 455)
  - Tape E44: House of Representatives Ron Dellums speech, 1988 August 11; 1 (Box 456)
  - Tape E44a: Beverly Hills, Undated; 1 (Box 457)
  - Tape E46: Durban skyline -- shot by Ken Kaplan, Undated; 1 (Box 458)
  - Tape E47: B-roll, exteriors of Council on Foreign Relations, ABC, and CBS News buildings, Undated; 1 (Box 459)
  - Tape E60: South Africa Now pull reel, Undated; 1 (Box 460)
  - Tape E61: Independent Television Network (ITN) Graphic, 1988 May 25; 1 (Box 461)
  - Tape E65: Kwitny Report, show #210, "The CIA," WNYC tape with WNYC logo, Undated; 1 (Box 462)
  - Tape E66: Boesak and Jackson at Riverside Church (shot very poorly), Undated; 1 (Box 463)
  - Tape E71: Rapitse; European Economic Community (EEC) meeting; African anthem; draft resisters press conference, 1988 December 16; 1 (Box 464)
  - Tape E73: Manhattan Borough President's Art Awards with Carolyn Craven, 1988 December 6; 1 (Box 465)
  - Tape E74: Stock footage -- establishing shots of Johannesburg -- commuters, women doing laundry, Undated; 1 (Box 466)
  - Tape E77: Rashid -- shots of October elections, Undated; 1 (Box 467)
  - Tape E78: Joseph Garba, United Nations Center Against Apartheid, 1988 November 28; 1 (Box 468)
  - Tapes E79-E80: Johnny Makatini memorial in NYC, tapes 1-2, 1988 December 16; 2 (Box 469–470)
  - Tape E81: Stills for 112 (including Happy News Year), 1988 December 19; 1 (Box 471)
  - Tape E82: Makatini funeral footage, 1988 December; 1 (Box 472)
  - Tape E86: NBC exterior, 30 Rockefeller Center, Undated; 1 (Box 473)
  - Tape E87: Johnny Makatini funeral service -- Lusaka, Zambia, 1988; 1 (Box 474)
  - Tape E88: Makatini: night vigil, body viewing, 1988 December 22; 1 (Box 475)
  - Tape E89: PAL versions of Makatini, 1988 December 22; 1 (Box 476)
  - Tapes E91-E92: Dub of Makatini service, 1988 December 22; 2 (Box 477–478)
  - Tape E93: Angola footage -- Cabinda Oil, helicopter, Undated; 1 (Box 479)
  - Tapes E96-E97: Tutu at Steven Wise Free Synagogue, Tapes 1 and 2, 1989 January 30; 2 (Box 480–481)
  - Tape E98: Citibank/Citicorp exteriors, tape 2 of 2, 1989 February 10; 1 (Box 482)
    There is no tape 1 of 2.
  - Tapes E99-E100: Qwa Qwa -- Repitse (tapes 1-2), 1989 February 15; 2 (Box 483–484)
  - Tape E101: Miners, 1988 December 18; 1 (Box 485)
  - Tape E102: Firing Line, 1989 February 6; 1 (Box 486)
  - Tape E104: South Africa Embassy, Washington D.C.; "Nkosi Sikeleli Africa", 1989 March 5; 1 (Box 487)
  - Tape E105: Soweto footage; "Shit River" Hunger Strike; Squatter Camp, Wits University, 1989 August 3; 1 (Box 488)
  - Tape E106: United Nations: Soviet flag; Japanese flag; Israeli flag, 1989 March 17; 1 (Box 489)
  - Aberdeen Proving Ground
    - Tape E107: From Center for Defense Information, Undated; 1 (Box 490)
    - Tape E108: From WUSA, Undated; 1 (Box 491)
  - Tape E109: Mobil Stations (New York), 1989 April 27; 1 (Box 492)
  - Tape E110: Mobil Stations (Johannesburg), 1989 April 29; 1 (Box 493)
  - Tape E111: Amsterdam Shell protests, 1989 May 1; 1 (Box 494)
  - Tape E112: Stiffel set-up; planes; New Jersey port, 1989 April 28; 1 (Box 495)
  - Tape E113: Eric's stand-up; New Jersey port, 1989 April 28; 1 (Box 496)
  - Tape E114: Sanctions Bust #1: b-roll, 1989 April 14; 1 (Box 497)
  - Tape E115: Sanctions Bust #2: Jet engines, 1989 April 21; 1 (Box 498)
  - Tape E116: Exterior Mobil Corporation headquarters -- 42nd St., New York City, 1989 May 4; 1 (Box 499)
  - Tape E117: Red Scorpion: b-roll of Times Square, etc., 1989 April 20; 1 (Box 500)
    See also: Tape L61.
  - Tape E118: B-roll Times Square, 1989 April 25; 1 (Box 501)
  - Tape E119: Harlem Hospital exteriors, 1989 May 18; 1 (Box 502)
  - Tape E121: World News Tonight open -- Peter Jennings, Undated; 1 (Box 503)
  - Tapes E124-E125: Namibia / Oxfam, Tapes 1 and 2, 1989 June; 2 (Box 504–505)
  - Tape E126: United Auto Workers (UAW) 29th Constitutional Convention -- Owen Bieber, Moses Mayakiso, 1989 June 22; 1 (Box 506)
  - Tape E128: UNTV -- Indonesia Foreign Minister -- General Assembly, 1989 July 21; 1 (Box 507)
  - Tape E129: UNTV -- United Nations (UN) Headquarters -- Geneva Exteriors, 1988 December 1; 1 (Box 508)
  - Tape E130: Angola TV: Huambo, 1989 August 29; 1 (Box 509)
  - Tape E131: NBC -- oil tanker footage, 1989 August 30; 1 (Box 510)
  - Tape E132: Cape Town docks and city shots, Undated; 1 (Box 511)
  - Tape E133: Washington shots of White House and Capitol, Undated; 1 (Box 512)
  - Tapes E135-E138: Anton Lubowski memorial, 1989 September 26; 4 (Box 513–516)
  - Tape E139: WABC -- Dinkins for Mayor, 1989 September 5; 1 (Box 517)
  - Tape E140: Tutu at Dinkins inauguration, 1990 January 1; 1 (Box 518)
  - Tape E141: WNYC -- Tutu at Dinkins inauguration with protesters, 1990 January 1; 1 (Box 519)
  - Tape E142: Tutu in Jerusalem, 1989 December; 1 (Box 520)
  - Tape E143: Old footage of Zimbabwe, Undated; 1 (Box 521)
  - Tape E144: Tutu visit to Jerusalem, 1989 December 25; 1 (Box 522)
  - Tapes E145-E146: World Vision: Mozambique refugee, tapes 1 and 2, 1990 March 16; 2 (Box 523–524)
  - Tape E147: Mozambique with Vonnegut, 1989; 1 (Box 525)
  - Tape E148-E149, E151: ABC -- African Project, parts 1-3, 1987 August 12; 3 (Box 526–528)
  - Tape E150: Zimbabwe Tourist Office, Undated; 1 (Box 529)
  - Tape E152: Front National de la Libération de l' Angola (FNLA) Troops, Undated; 1 (Box 530)
  - Tape E153: Police brutality in Bophuthatswana, Undated; 1 (Box 531)
  - Tape E154: Botswana Conference, 1987 August 4; 1 (Box 532)
  - Tape E155: Images of Africa, Undated; 1 (Box 533)
  - Tape E157: World News Tonight -- Secretary of State James Baker; Short segments on T. Chapman, Patti Labelle at Mandela Concert, Wembley, 1990 May 2; 1 (Box 534)
  - Tape E158: Viral Lab -- NBC news footage, 1990 April 18; 1 (Box 535)
  - Tape E159: "Bug Bombs" -- NBC story, 1990 May 11; 1 (Box 536)
  - Tape E160: "Race for Change" (dub), 1986 September 6; 1 (Box 537)
  - Tape E161: Pathfinder Mural, Undated; 1 (Box 538)
  - Tape E162: Zimbabwe nature footage, including elephants (Christian Science Monitor), 1988 May 13; 1 (Box 539)
  - Tape E163: Callaghan: Sting Operation (FBI), Undated; 1 (Box 540)
  - Tape E164: Comex -- B-Roll, Undated; 1 (Box 541)
  - Tape E165: Debswana mine, Undated; 1 (Box 542)
  - Tape E166: Nujoma highlights of visit to U.S., Undated; 1 (Box 543)
  - Tape E168: Accuracy in media; Winnie Mandela's secret, Undated; 1 (Box 544)
  - Tapes E168-E169: De Klerk visit to Washington, 1990 September 24; 2 (Box 545–546)
    The same tape number (E168) was assigned to two different recordings.
  - Tape E170: Frank Fredricks runs in Namibia, 1990 Spring; 1 (Box 547)
  - Tape E171: D. Harmon, "Saving the Cheetah", 1990 August 16; 1 (Box 548)
  - Tape E172: United Nations (UN) exteriors; De Klerk in U.S. stills, Undated; 1 (Box 549)
  - Tape E173: Namibia -- shots of Nujoma, etc., 1990 August 24; 1 (Box 550)
  - Tapes E174-E176: African American Business Leadership/ South Africa (commercial ties, stocks), 1990 October 11; 3 (Box 551–553)
  - Tape E177: African American/South African Business (Dinkins), 1990 October 10; 1 (Box 554)
  - Tape E178: African American/South African Business Leaders, 1990 October 9; 1 (Box 555)
  - Tape E179: African American/South African Business Interest groups, 1990 October 9; 1 (Box 556)
  - Tapes E180-E183: American Public Health Conference (AIDS), tapes 1-4, 1990 September 28; 4 (Box 557–560)
  - Tape E184: Writers' Union Conference, 1990 October 14; 1 (Box 561)
  - Tapes E185-E186: CSPAN -- House floor coverage, tapes 1 and 2, 1990 October 17; 2 (Box 562–563)
  - Tape E187: St. Paul City Council; Zolile, 1990 September 25; 1 (Box 564)
  - Tape E188: Frank Fredricks -- Namibian runner (United States Information Agency [USIA]), 1990 September 24; 1 (Box 565)
  - Tape E189: "Terror" Lekota -- stills of squatters, 1990; 1 (Box 566)
  - Tape E190: University of California, Berkeley Conference: Civil Land Rights/Distribution/Homelands/Farming (Lekota), Undated; 1 (Box 567)
  - Tape E192: Press conference -- David Dinkins; Lindwe Mbuza speaking at Riverside Church celebrating Mandela, Undated; 1 (Box 568)
  - Tape E194: South African Embassy demonstration, United Auto Workers (UAW), Undated; 1 (Box 569)
  - Tape E195: Diamonds; Premier Prince of Pipes, Undated; 1 (Box 570)
  - Tape E196: Oliver Tambo at Riverside Church, 1987; 1 (Box 571)
  - Tape E197: President Mugabe convocation -- Michigan State University, 1990 September 28; 1 (Box 572)
  - Tape E198: Operation Hunger -- Ina Perlman, 1989; 1 (Box 573)
  - Tape E199: South African Security Alarms, Undated; 1 (Box 574)
- Interviews, 1978-1991, undated; Series V
  The series includes raw footage of interviews conducted in the process of producing South Africa Now. Interview subjects include various South African political and cultural figures including Nelson Mandela, Desmond Tutu, Thabo Mbeki, Albie Sachs, Athol Fugard, Hugh Masekela, and many others. There are also interviews with Americans and others interested in South African affairs and the anti-apartheid movement, including Jesse Jackson and David Dinkins. It is arranged sequentially by a tape numbering system used by Globalvision and tape titles used by Globalvision have been preserved. Listed at the end of the series, there are four boxes of logbooks that provide greater details about the interviews.
  - Tape F1: Mbuelo, Linda, Undated; 1 (Box 575)
  - Tape F2: Jennifer Davis and Bill Johnson, Undated; 1 (Box 576)
  - Tapes F3-F5: Mark Swilling, 1988 April 22; 3 (Box 577–579)
  - Tapes F5-F6: Bobby Godsell, 1988 April 22; 2 (Box 579–580)
  - Tapes F7-F12: Desmond Tutu, tapes 1-6, 1988 April 29; 6 (Box 581–586)
  - Tapes F13-F14: Mary de Almeida, Undated; 2 (Box 587–588)
  - Tapes F14-F16: Nujoma, Undated; 3 (Box 588–590)
  - Tapes F16-F17: Damou Smith, Undated; 2 (Box 590–591)
  - Tapes F18-F19: Coke McCord, Undated; 2 (Box 592–593)
  - Tapes F19-F20: Julie Cliff, Undated; 2 (Box 593–594)
  - Tapes F21-F23: Dennis Goldberg, tapes 1-3, Undated; 3 (Box 595–597)
  - Tapes F24-F25: Nina Overton, tapes 1-2, Undated; 2 (Box 598–599)
  - Tapes F26-F27: Lionel Rogosin, tapes 1-2, Undated; 2 (Box 600–601)
  - Tapes F28-F30: Nadine Gordimer, tapes 1-3, Undated; 3 (Box 602–604)
  - Tape F32: Gordon Sibiya -- Nuclear Physicist, Undated; 1 (Box 606)
  - Tapes F33-F34: James Brook, tapes 1 and 2, Undated; 2 (Box 607–608)
  - Tape F35: Shawn Slovo, 1988 June 14; 1 (Box 609)
  - Tapes F35-F36: Linda Mvusi, parts 1 and 2, 1988 June 14; 2 (Box 609–610)
  - Tape F36: Chris Menges, 1988 June 14; 1 (Box 610)
  - Tape F37: Interview -- Harlem (Désir) of SOS Racisme, Undated; 1 (Box 611)
  - Tape F38: Jonathan Demme; S. Masuras, 1988 June 15; 1 (Box 612)
  - Tape F39: Jonas Savimbi, Undated; 1 (Box 613)
  - Tape F40: Angolan Foreign Minister, 1988 June 24; 1 (Box 614)
  - Tape F41: Miriam Lacobe, Undated; 1 (Box 615)
  - Tape F42: Little Steven Van Zandt, 1988 June 24; 1 (Box 616)
  - Tape F43: Bill Bowles and Mweli, Undated; 1 (Box 617)
  - Tapes F44-F45: Eric Goldstein, Undated; 2 (Box 618–619)
  - Tape F47: Reverend Ben Chavis, 1988 July 2; 1 (Box 620)
  - Tapes F48-F49: Jon Alpert, 1988 July 1; 2 (Box 621–622)
  - Tapes F49-F50: Elombe Brath, 1988 July 1; 2 (Box 622–623)
  - Tape F51: Bill Bowles on Angola, 1988 July 5 (Box 624)
  - Tape F52: Phillip Van Niekirk and Tony Weaver, Undated; 1 (Box 625)
  - Tapes F53-F54: Dennis Goldberg, African National Congress (ANC), tapes 1-2, Undated; 2 (Box 626–627)
  - Tape F55: Mike Maren, 1988 July 16; 1 (Box 628)
  - Tape F56: Heinz Klug, 1988 July 16; 1 (Box 629)
  - Tape F57: Paul David and Sakhile, Undated; 1 (Box 630)
  - Tape F58: Michael Clough, Undated; 1 (Box 631)
  - Tape F59: Bert Carlson, Undated; 1 (Box 632)
  - Tapes F60-F61: John Makatini, tapes 1 and 2, Undated; 2 (Box 633–634)
  - Tapes F62-F64: Hugh Masekela, tapes 1-3, Undated; 3 (Box 635–637)
  - Tapes F65-F66: S. Mosouris, tapes 1-2, Undated; 2 (Box 638–639)
    Tape 2 (box 639) also includes United Nations (UN) b-roll.
  - Tapes F67-F68: Hammer, Undated; 2 (Box 640–641)
  - Tape F69: Prexy Nesbit, Undated; 1 (Box 642)
    Audio is poor on mist of the tape.
  - Tape F70: Representative Porter, 1988 August 11; 1 (Box 643)
  - Tape F71: Joyce Mochesi, 1988 August 15; 1 (Box 644)
  - Tapes F72-F73: Damu Smith, tapes 1-2, 1988 August 14; 2 (Box 645–646)
  - Tape F73: Ken Zin, 1988 August 14; 1 (Box 646)
  - Tape F74: Thabo Mbeki, 1988 August 30; 1 (Box 647)
  - Tape F76: Dr. Wilkinson and Calley Crossley, Undated; 1 (Box 648)
  - Tape F77: Nigel Noble, Sarafina, Undated; 1 (Box 649)
  - Tape F78: Anton Lubowski, South West Africa People's Organization (SWAPO), 1988 September 15; 1 (Box 650)
  - Tape F79: Gwen Lister, Undated; 1 (Box 651)
  - Tape F80: Toiva ja Toiva of South West Africa People's Organization (SWAPO), 1988 September 15; 1 (Box 652)
  - Tape F81: Pam Falk (on Angola), Undated; 1 (Box 653)
  - Tape F82: Nick Claxton (director of Suffer the Children ), Undated; 1 (Box 654)
    Also includes clips of film, shot of Turnley.
  - Tapes F84-F85: Tjallingi -- interview, newspapers, stills, photos, Undated; 2 (Box 655–656)
  - Tape F87: Johnny Clegg -- Athens, Undated; 1 (Box 657)
  - Tape F89: Michael Clough, 1988 September 28; 1 (Box 658)
  - Tape F90: Steve Mufson, 1988 September 28; 1 (Box 659)
  - Tape F128: Interview with Bill Finnegan, 1988 November 18; 1 (Box 660)
    See also: Tape 165, box 683.
  - Tapes F140-F143: Boesak -- sermon, tapes 1-4 (cutaways, sermon, church exterior), 1988 October 30; 4 (Box 661–664)
  - Tape F146: Patrick Tandy -- South African draft dodger, 1988 November 3; 1 (Box 665)
  - Tapes F147-F149: Brenda Danilowitz, Undated; 3 (Box 666–668)
  - Tape F149: Richard Knight (on Japanese trade with South Africa), Undated; 1 (Box 668)
  - Tapes F150-F151: Sergio Viera, 1988 November 4; 2 (Box 669–670)
  - Tapes F152-F153: Rose Moss, 1988 November 9; 2 (Box 671–672)
  - Tape F154: Slabert WGBH interview, 1988 October 31; 1 (Box 673)
  - Tape F155: Joseph Diescho, 1988 November 10; 1 (Box 674)
  - Tapes F156-F158: Helen Sebidi, Undated; 3 (Box 675–677)
  - Tape F159: Derek Bauer drawing, Undated; 1 (Box 678)
    See also: Tape F160, box 679 and Tapes F169-F171, boxes 686-688.
  - Tape F160: Derek Bauer interview (early one), Undated; 1 (Box 679)
    See also: Tape F159, box 678 and Tapes F169-F171, boxes 686-688.
  - Tape F161: Randall Robinson, 1988 November 10; 1 (Box 680)
  - Tapes F162-F163: Johnny Clegg interview, 1-2, 1988 November 12; 2 (Box 681–682)
  - Tape F165: Bill Finnegan (author of Dateline Soweto ), 1988 November 18; 1 (Box 683)
    See also: Tape F128, box 660.
  - Tapes F167-F168: Ambassador to United Nations (UN) from Ghana, tapes 1-2, 1988 November 18; 2 (Box 684–685)
  - Tapes F169-F171: Derek Bauer, 1988 November 18; 3 (Box 686–688)
    See also: Tape F159, box 678 and Tape F160, box 679.
    F171 (box 688) contains no audio.
  - Tape F173: Michael Clough and Guriab, 1988 November 21; 1 (Box 689)
  - Tape F174: Dinkins interview; also stills, articles, 1988 November 21; 1 (Box 690)
  - Tapes F177-F178: Professor Kunene (University of California, Los Angeles) for Shaka, 1988 November 15; 2 (Box 691–692)
  - Tape F179: Richard Pryor, Hear No Evil, See No Evil, 1988 November 16; 1 (Box 693)
  - Tapes F180-F181: David Pallister, 1988 November 24; 2 (Box 694–695)
  - Tapes F184-F185: James Stuart (of African National Congress [ANC]) from Mosaic -- Zambia, tapes 1-2, Undated; 2 (Box 696–697)
  - Tapes F186-F187: Mary Burton (National President of Black Sash), 1988 December 2; 2 (Box 698–699)
  - Tapes F188-F189: Nicholas Ndebele (Director of Catholic Commission for Justice and Peace in Zimbabwe), 1988 December 2; 2 (Box 700–701)
  - Tape F190: Professor Corey, Undated; 1 (Box 702)
  - Reebok statement and interview
    - Desmond Tutu
      - Tape F191, 1988 March 12; 1 (Box 703)
      - Tape F192, 1988 December 6; 1 (Box 704)
    - Tape F193: Boesak, 1988 December 6; 1 (Box 705)
    - Tape F194: Beyers Naude, 1988 December 6; 1 (Box 706)
    - Tape F195: Frank Chikane, Undated; 1 (Box 707)
  - Tapes F196-F199: Reebok Breakfast footage, 1988 December 7; 4 (Box 708–711)
  - Tape F210: Studio shoot -- Sheila Gordon and stills, 1988 November 28; 1 (Box 712)
  - Tape F212: Raymond Louw, 1988 December 5; 1 (Box 713)
  - Tapes F213-F214: David Coplan, Undated; 2 (Box 714–715)
  - Tapes F216-F217: Dumile, 1988 December 8; 2 (Box 716–717)
    Tape F217 (box 717) contains a six-minute content break begining 7.5 minutes into tape.
  - Tape F219: Tebogo Mafole, African National Congress (ANC), 1988 December 8; 1 (Box 718)
    See also: Tapes F224-F225, boxes 720-721.
  - Tape F221: Salim Karim, 1988 December 9; 1 (Box 719)
  - Tapes F224-F225: Tebogo Mafole, African National Congress (ANC), tapes 1-2, 1988 December 12; 2 (Box 720–721)
    See also: Tape F219, box 718.
  - Tape F226: Eric Goldstein, 1988 December 14; 1 (Box 722)
  - Tapes F229-F230: Sam Nujoma, tapes 1-2, 1989 December 17; 2 (Box 723–724)
  - Tapes F231-F232: Mohammed Valli Moosa, tapes 1-2, 1989 January 29; 2 (Box 725–726)
  - Tape F233: Murphy Marobe, 1989 January 29; 1 (Box 727)